<messages>

 <message name="Sound Data"><text><![CDATA[
 <p>The top of the <strong>Edit Sound Data</strong> form provides an overview of administrative information associated with your file; i. e., it lists the file name and the ID number of the media file in the ToL database, and it keeps track of who contributed the file and who last edited the data.</p>
 
  <p>You have the option to  <strong>Upload a thumbnail image for this sound</strong>, which will then be used to represent your sound file on ToL web pages.  If you do not provide a thumbnail, a generic sound icon will be used.</p>
   <p>If you find a flaw in a sound file you have uploaded, or if a better version of your file becomes available, you can use the <strong>Replace this sound with a new version</strong> link to upload the revised file.   
</p>                  
                    ]]></text>
</message> 

<message name="Copyright Owner">
<text><![CDATA[<p>As a general rule, the creator of a sound file owns 
						  the copyright and has the exclusive right of distribution. You don't have 
						  to register your work with any authority or agency in order to have it protected by copyright law.</p>
						  <p>The 
						  copyright of the creator may be limited if the material in question 
						  was created as a 'work made for hire', or if the copyright has previously 
						  been relinquished to a publisher.</p>
						  
<p>When you upload a new sound file to the ToL database, you will be listed as the copyright owner by default.  If you upload a sound file for which you do not own the copyright, you need to select another option in the <strong>Copyright Information</strong> section:</p>						  
						  
<ul>
<li>If the person or institution who owns the copyright is a registered ToL contributor, you should use the <strong>Select a Contributor</strong> link to locate the contributor in the ToL database.  You should use this tool, rather than typing the person's name in the <em>Copyright Owner</em> text field below, because it ensures that the sound file gets linked to all the other information about the contributor in the ToL database.</li>
<li>If the copyright owner is not a registered ToL 
      Contributor, you can type the person's name in the <em>Copyright Owner</em> text field. Also, you 
      can provide their e-mail address and/or home page url, which will then be 
      used to create a link in the copyright notice.</li>
<li>Use the <strong>No copyright owner</strong> option only if you are sure that a sound file is in the public domain, i.e., nobody can claim the right to limit the 
      distribution of this file.</li>
</ul>
<p>Enter the four-digit year for the copyright 
      date. You are not required to provide a copyright date, but it's part of 
      a proper copyright notice. Generally, it's good to use the date of creation 
      or the date of first publication as the copyright date.</p>						  
						  
						  ]]></text>
</message>                            

<message name="Use Permitted by Copyright Owner">
<text><![CDATA[
						
<p>When you contribute a sound file to the ToL project, we ask you to give us 
        a license specifying how the file can be used. In order 
        to meet the needs of a diverse community of contributors, we provide a variety of different 
        options regarding the publication and potential reuse of your sound file. 
    </p>
    <p>In the <strong>Edit Sound Data</strong> form, you can click on the text next to a radio button to get a detailed explanation of each option.</p>
								<p> You can change the default license applied to your future media contributions by checking the <strong>Remember this option for my future contributions</strong> box.  </p>
		<p>Note that the <strong>Use Permitted by Copyright Owner</strong> section is active only for works protected by copyright.  If you have selected <strong>No copyright owner</strong> above, the public domain option is selected automatically.</p>									
								]]></text>
</message>    



<message name="Other Credits">
<text><![CDATA[
  
<ul>
 <li><strong>Acknowledgements</strong>: Here you can acknowledge any person or institution 
      that has facilitated the creation or distribution of the sound file.</li> 
      <li><strong>Creator</strong>: You can use this field to give credit to the person who created the sound file. In most cases, the copyright owner and the creator will be the same person, and it's not necessary to credit the creator separately.</li>     
 
 <li><strong>Reference/Source</strong>: Click on the Reference/Source header to open up the section where you can edit this information.
 <ul>
  <li><strong>Reference</strong>: If this sound file is part of a previously published media collection, 
      please provide the reference here.  Note that you should not copy and submit other people's sound files unless you have their permission or the work is licensed under creative commons or is in the public domain.</li>
  <li><strong>Source</strong>: If you have copied this sound file from another website, please provide relevant information here. The <strong>Title of Source File</strong> should be the file name or the title of the page on which the source file is featured. The <strong>Url of Source File</strong> should ideally be the url of the page that provides access to the source file and any data associated with the source file. Select the <strong>Source Collection</strong> from the menu, or enter the relevant data for a new source collection in the <strong>Collection</strong> (name of the collection) and <strong>Homepage</strong> fields. Please try to avoid duplicate entries of source collections.</li>     
         
  </ul></li>    
</ul>  
  
      ]]></text>
</message>                        


<message name="Attached to Group(s)">
<text><![CDATA[<p>When you click on the <strong>Add a Group from the ToL Database</strong> link, you will be able to search for the names of groups in the ToL database.  Please attach your file to that 
        group in the Tree of Life to which it is most relevant.  </p> 
        
        <p>If you have a sound file featuring a specimen of a certain species and that species is represented 
        in the ToL database, you should attach it to this species. If the species 
        is not yet represented in the ToL database, you should attach your file 
        to the group that is closest to the species, e.g., the genus or the family 
        that the species belongs to.  If your file is relevant to more than one group (e. g., if it features specimens of two different species), you can attach it to each of these groups.</p>
      <p>Attaching media files in the ToL database to groups in the tree will allow people to find resources based on phylogenetic criteria.  For example, when you attach a file of a frog call to the node of its species, e.g., <em>Rana ridibunda</em>, people will find this file not only if they search for <em>Rana ridibunda</em> sounds, but also if they search for sounds of Western Palearctic water frogs, frogs in general, amphibians, vertebrates, animals etc.</p>
]]></text>
</message>	


   <message name="Media Content"><text><![CDATA[
   <p>Please be sure to provide a <strong>Title</strong> that concisely and accurately describes the content of your sound file.  You can also provide a more detailed <strong>Description</strong> that can serve as an abstract for your sound file.</p>
<p> You can also check one or more features that describe the content of your file as well as relevant subjects and key words. 
</p><p>   If you go through the trouble of providing detailed metadata about the content of your media file, our media database will get better organized, and it will be easier for ToL visitors and page authors to find the media they are most interested in.
For example, somebody looking for a sounds made by beetle larvae would probably want to focus their search on sound files attached to a group in the Coleoptera branch that have the <strong>Organism Sound</strong>, <strong>Neurobiology & Behavior</strong> and <strong>Life History & Development</strong> options selected.

</p>                 
                    ]]></text>
</message>                     

   <message name="Place and Time"><text><![CDATA[
   
 <ul>
 <li><strong>Location</strong>: For organism and environmental sounds, provide information about the location where the sound file was recorded. If the organism featured in the recording was found in a different location, this information may be more relevant than the place where the recording was made.  If the organism is not native to the location where it was found, you may also want to provide information about its origin.</li>
  <li><strong>Date/Time</strong>: For some recordings, it may be good to know when exactly they were created.  For example, when a sound was recorded will tell you things like when an organism is out and about in a given location, when an animal is displaying a certain behavior, etc.</li>
 </ul>

                    ]]></text>
</message>     


<message name="Specimen Information">
<text><![CDATA[
<p>If your recording features specimens of organisms, providing some information about these specimens will make your media file a more valuable resource. </p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Scientific Name</strong>: If the species of a specimen featured in your recording is not yet represented in the ToL database, you should provide the scientific name of this species here.  This will allow us to attach your media file to the species as soon as it is added to the ToL database.  If your file features organisms 
      belonging to different groups, you can enter the scientific name of each organism 
      and separate individual entries with commas.</li>
<li><strong>Identified By</strong>: You can provide the name of the person who identified 
      the specimen.  This field is particularly useful, if this person is a known expert of the group.</li>
<li><strong>Behavior</strong>:  Here you can provide information about the behavior 
      displayed by the organism featured in your recording. Possible kinds of behavior 
      are courtship, mating, feeding, alarm, distress, conflict, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Sex</strong>: The calls of male and female organisms are often distinct. Enter this information only if you are sure you know 
      the sex of the specimen.</li>
<li><strong>Life Cycle Stage</strong>:  Here you can indicate whether the specimen is 
      a juvenile or adult. You can also enter more specific information, e.g., 
      second instar larva, pupa, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Body Part</strong>: If the sound you recorded was produced by a particular body part, you can record this information here.</li>
<li><strong>Specimen Documentation</strong>: This section contains fields that are generally relevant only for taxonomists.</li>
</ul>]]>
</text>
</message>


<message name="Specimen Documentation">
<text><![CDATA[
<p>This section contains fields that are generally relevant only for taxonomists. </p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Collection</strong>:   If the specimen is part of a collection, you 
      can provide information about this collection here.</li>
<li><strong>Type</strong>: If this is a type specimen (a specimen on which 
      the original published description of a species is based), you can provide 
      information on whether it is a holotype, paratype, syntype, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Voucher Number</strong>: If the specimen is part of a voucher collection, 
      you can enter the voucher number here.</li>
<li><strong>Voucher Collection</strong>:  Provide a reference for the voucher collection.</li>
<li><strong>Collector</strong>: Provide the name of the person who collected 
      the specimen.</li>
</ul> ]]>
</text>
</message>

       <message name="Comments"><text><![CDATA[
                        Here you can enter any information about your 
sound file that you think may be of interest but that is not covered in any of 
      the other fields in this form.
                    ]]></text>
</message>   



<message name="Alternative Text">
<text><![CDATA[You can provide a transcript to take the place of your movie or sound for people using a text-only web browser.
]]></text>
</message>                                                                                                                                                                            
<message name="Sound Type">
<text><![CDATA[
<ul>
<li>Select <strong>Natural Sound</strong> for unaltered organism and environmental sounds.</li>
<li>Select <strong>Speech</strong> for recordings of human speech.    </li>
<li>Select <strong>Music</strong> for recordings of sounds created by singing humans and musical instruments. </li>
<li>Select <strong>Articial Sound Effect</strong> for recordings that have been artificially altered.</li>
      <li>Select <strong>Mixed</strong> if your recording features more than one of the above components.</li>
<li>Check the <strong>Fiction/Performance/Artistic representation</strong> box if the major purpose of your sound file is not the scientifically accurate illustration of organisms' features or behaviors.</li>
<li>You can also provide technical information about your sound recording, its running time and the language of any featured human speech.</li>
</ul>

                    ]]></text>
</message>                                                                                                                                            
                                                                                                                                        
                    <message name="Editing Privileges"><text><![CDATA[

                        <p>By default only the media contributor, the copyright 
      owner (if a registered ToL contributor), and ToL editors in charge of media 
      administration have editing privileges for the data associated with a given 
      media file. You can use this list to provide editing privileges to other ToL 
      contributors, e.g., your co-authors for ToL pages or people who collaborate 
      with you in the identification of the organisms in your media files.</p>
                    ]]></text>
</message>                                                                                                                                            
                    <message name="Notes"><text><![CDATA[
                        <p>The <strong>Notes</strong> field 
        should be used for internal ToL communication about your media file. You can 
        use this field to leave reminders for yourself or messages to ToL editors. Also, 
        other ToL contributors will have access to this field and can leave messages 
        for you about your file (not yet implemented). For example, somebody may let you know if they 
        think an organism is misidentified or they may be able to provide additional 
        information that is not included in your original sound data. After reviewing 
        the information provided by other contributors, you can decide whether 
        you want to use it to revise your sound data.</p>

      <p>The content of this field is not printed on the ToL web site along with 
        other sound data. Also, the general ToL Media Search ignores the <strong>Notes</strong>         text. However, when you do a search across all sound data fields in the 
        ToL Media Manager, the text of the <strong>Notes</strong> field will be included.</p>
                    ]]></text>
</message>                                                                                                                                            
                         
                                              
</messages>